Ashraf Ayman Abdulmageed

Email: ashrafayman219@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://ashrafayman219.github.io/GIS-PORTFOLIO

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashraf-ayman

+20 1014311398

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a GIS Developer with 3 years of expertise in GIS technologies (focus on ESRI products), web development and GIS Integration, with a strong commitment to GIS development industry. Proven proficiency in ArcGIS API for JavaScript, Python scripting, GeoServer, GIS capabilities such Spatial Analysis and data collection. My goal is to excel as a GIS Developer and collaborate on exciting projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIS Developer,

Gulf Terminal, Mansoura, Egypt

May 2023 - Present

- o Created esri-Library (APIs) based on ArcGIS Maps SDK for JavaScript for building GIS web apps and spatial analysis applications for 2D and 3D visualization.
- Designs, develops, and maintains software using ESRI software suite as well as programming tools.
- o Developed programming specifications for assigned tasks.
- Gained possess strong knowledge of database concepts and RDBMS like Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, etc.
- o Performs database design modifications.
- o Tests system and confers with Project Managers to assure satisfaction.
- o Created program source code; performs standardized validation tests; and debugs code when issues are identified.

GIS Developer,

Edge Pro for Information Systems, Cairo, Egypt

Jun 2022 - Feb 2023

- o Developed and implemented customized client requirements and created GIS demos for clients.
- o Familiar with ArcGIS API for JavaScript, Esri Technologies, JavaScript, Python and SQL.
- o Participated in a GIS and RS project to be presented at COP 27, Sharm Elsheikh 2022.
- o Familiar with ArcSDE, RDBMS, ArcGIS Sever, SQL Server, PostgreSQL.
- o Familiar with Hexagon Technologies, ERDAS Imagine.
- o Cooperate and communicate with relevant external bodies.
- o Work closely with other developers and architects.

GIS Specialist,

Edge Pro for Information Systems, Cairo, Egypt

Apr 2022 - Jun 2022

- o Compiled geographic data from a variety of sources including censuses, field observation, satellite imagery, aerial photographs, and existing maps.
- o I analyzed spatial data for geographic statistics to incorporate into documents and reports.
- o To define data needs, project requirements, required outputs, or to develop applications.

- o Gather, analyze, and integrate spatial data from staff and determine how best the information can be displayed using GIS.
- Design and update database, applying additional knowledge of spatial feature representations.

SKILLS

o GIS Software / Development:

ArcGIS API for JS
 ArcGIS Enterprise (Server, Portal, Online)
 ArcGIS Pro
 M.App Enterprise
 GeoServer
 Leaflet
 PostgreSQL
 Open Layers
 Mapbox

OGIS

Programming:

Python
 JavaScript (Intermediate, focus on ArcGIS

 API for JS)
 JavaScript Runtime Environment
 TypeScript (Beginner)
 OOP
 Git and GitHub
 ASP.NET Core
 MS SQL Server
 SQL (Beginner)

o HTML/CSS

Angular (Beginner)C# (Beginner)

o Remote Sensing Software:

- o ERDAS Imagine
- o ENVI
- o Knowledge of LIDAR data processing and feature extraction

EDUCATION

5 Months Intensive Training Program of GIS and Web Development

Information Technology Institute (ITI), Smart Village, Egypt, 2022

o Final Project: "Business Solutions Web App," co-authored with Ahmed Ashraf, Ahmed Mesbah, and Shady Mamdouh. Created web application for analyze spatial data with time series analysis, to achieve business owner's criteria with innovative GIS-based solutions using ArcGIS Enterprise (Online-Portal-Server), ESRI APIs and Web Development technologies.

Bachelor of Arts, Department of Surveying, Remote Sensing & GIS

Mansoura University, 2021

- o Graduation Project: "Simulation Model of the Faculty of Arts," using ArcGIS Pro, Excellent Grade
- o GPA: 3.7
- o Rank 2 on my faculty batch

Evening Digital Egypt Youth Program, Front-End Web Development track

National Telecommunication Institute (NTI), 2023

o **Top skills learned:** Bootstrap, jQuery and JavaScript.

ACADEMIC HONORS

Bachelor's degree in GIS and Remote Sensing Honours from Mansoura University, 2021.

EVENTS

I attended Esri Saudi Arabia User Conference Day (23 Jan 2024).

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Arabic: Native Language English: Very Good

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Birthdate: April. 1st, 1999 Military Status: Exempted

Current Address: Mansoura, Ad Dakahlia, Egypt

Thank you for your time.

I would love to hear from you if you are at all further interested in my work.

References available upon request.